<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="commands.css"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="commands.xsl"?>
<COMMAND>
    <NAME>task</NAME>
    <SUMMARY>Spawn a Tcl shell in a new process and run the provided command in it or send data to a running task.</SUMMARY>
    <DESCRIPTION>If there is no task running in <VAR>bufferName</VAR>
    	start one running by passing <VAR>taskData</VAR> to a Tcl shell.
    	If there is a task running, place <VAR>taskData</VAR> on its stdin.<BR/>
		The task command runs a command-line expression asynchronously in a
		separate Tcl shell. When the process has finished the optional
		<VAR>completionProc</VAR> will be called in e93 with <VAR>bufferName</VAR> (the name of the buffer the task
		was running in) and the exit status the process returned. A buffer may
		only have one task running at a time. Multiple buffers can each have
		their own concurrent task.
	</DESCRIPTION>
    <PARAMETER>
        <NAME>bufferName</NAME>The unique name of an e93 buffer.</PARAMETER>
    <PARAMETER>
        <NAME>taskData</NAME>The data to be sent to a running sub-shell or, initially, the command-line used to start that process.</PARAMETER>
    <PARAMETER optional="true">
        <NAME>completionProc</NAME>
        The name of a Tcl proc that will be called when the task has finished running. That proc is expected to accept two parameters. <VAR>bufferName</VAR> (the name of the buffer the task
		was running in) and the exit status the process returned.
    </PARAMETER>
    <STATUS>This command will return an error in the following cases:<BR/>
        <VAR>bufferName</VAR> is not provided.<BR/>
        <VAR>bufferName</VAR> is not an e93 buffer.<BR/>
        <VAR>taskData</VAR> is not provided.<BR/></STATUS>
    <SEEALSO>
        <CODE>
            <A HREF="detatchtask.html">detatchtask</A>
            <A HREF="eoftask.html">eoftask</A>
            <A HREF="hastask.html">hastask</A>
            <A HREF="killtask.html">killtask</A>
            <A HREF="taskbytes.html">taskbytes</A>
            <A HREF="updatetask.html">updatetask</A>
        </CODE>
    </SEEALSO>
</COMMAND>
