<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="chapters.css"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="chapters.xsl"?>

<CHAPTER>
<TITLE>
About the e93 Command Reference
</TITLE>

<SUMMARY>
An explanation of the conventions used in this document
</SUMMARY>

<BODY>
	<P>The <I>e93 Command Reference</I> is a command dictionary that describes each of the built-in commands and many of the procs available for use with e93.</P>
	<H3>
	<A NAME="sections"></A>
	Sections of the Reference
	</H3>
	<BLOCKQUOTE>
		<P>
		For each entry, the reference begins with a heading line that includes
		the command name and a label indicating whether the command is a proc,
		or built-in command.
		</P>
		<P>
		For each command, the reference provides the following information:<BR />
		<!-- Table Start -->
		<TABLE BORDER="0" CELLSPACING="0" CELLPADDING="0">
			<TR>
				<TH WIDTH="200">
					Section Title
				</TH>
				<TH>
					Description
				</TH>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
					<B><A HREF="#syntax">SYNOPSIS</A></B>
				</TD>
				<TD>
					a concise listing of the syntax for invoking the command
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
					<B><A HREF="#description">DESCRIPTION</A></B>
				</TD>
				<TD>
					an explanation of the command's function
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<!-- no input sections for now
			<TR>
				<TD>
					<B><A HREF="#input">INPUT</A></B>
				</TD>
				<TD>
					information on the command's input, if any
				</TD>
			</TR>
			-->
			<TR>
				<TD>
					<B><A HREF="#output">OUTPUT</A></B>
				</TD>
				<TD>
					information on the command's output, if any
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
					<B><A HREF="#status">STATUS</A></B>
				</TD>
				<TD>
					a list of possible status codes and their meanings
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
					<B><A HREF="#parameters">PARAMETERS</A></B>
				</TD>
				<TD>
					a description of each of the command's parameters
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
					<B><A HREF="#options">OPTIONS</A></B>
				</TD>
				<TD>
					a description of each of the command's options
				</TD>
			</TR>
		</TABLE>
		<!-- Table End -->
		</P>

		<P>For some commands, the reference also includes these sections:
		<!-- Table Start -->
		<TABLE BORDER="0" CELLSPACING="0" CELLPADDING="0">
			<TR>
				<TH WIDTH="200">
					Section Title
				</TH>
				<TH>
					Description
				</TH>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
					<B><A HREF="#examples">EXAMPLES</A></B>
				</TD>
				<TD>
					examples of how to use the command
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
					<B><A HREF="#limitations">LIMITATIONS</A></B>
				</TD>
				<TD>
					a list of limitations, special cases, or warnings
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
					<B><A HREF="#seealso">SEE ALSO</A></B>
				</TD>
				<TD>
					references to related commands or information
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
					<B><A HREF="#location">LOCATION</A></B>
				</TD>
				<TD>
					the .tcl file that contains the proc
				</TD>
			</TR>
		</TABLE>
		<!-- Table End -->
		</P>
	</BLOCKQUOTE>
	<H3>
	<A NAME="syntax"></A>
	SYNOPSIS
	</H3>
	<BLOCKQUOTE>
		<P>
		This section lists the complete syntax for the command, in the general form
		</P>
		<CODE>
		Command <VAR>?parameter...? ?option...?</VAR>
		</CODE>
		<P>
		where <CODE>Command</CODE> is the name of the proc, or built-in command; <VAR>parameter...</VAR>
		is a list of one or more parameters; and <VAR>option...</VAR> is a list of one or more options.
		</P>
		
		<P />

		<P CLASS="TableTitle">
		e93 syntax conventions</P>
		<!-- Table Start -->
		<TABLE BORDER="0" CELLSPACING="0" CELLPADDING="0">
			<TR>
				<TD WIDTH="200">
				<CODE>
				? ?
				</CODE>
				</TD>
				<TD>
				Question marks indicate optional elements; other elements must be specified.
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
				...
				</TD>
				<TD>
				Ellipses (...) indicate the preceding item can be repeated one or more times in a list separated by spaces or tabs.
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
				<VAR>italics</VAR>
				</TD>
				<TD>
				Italics indicate a parameter that you must replace with anything that matches the parameter's definition.
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
				<CODE>
				|
				</CODE>
				</TD>
				<TD>
				A vertical bar (<CODE>|</CODE>) indicates an either/or choice.
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
				<CODE>
				literal
				</CODE>
				</TD>
				<TD>
				Courier text indicates a word that must appear exactly as shown.
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
				<CODE>
				<B>off</B>
				</CODE>
				</TD>
				<TD>
				Bold elements indicate the default setting of the command or option.
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
				<CODE>
				<P>-</P>
				</CODE>
				</TD>
				<TD>
				A hyphen (<CODE>-</CODE>) always precedes an option and is a required part of the option.
				</TD>
			</TR>
		</TABLE>
		<!-- Table End -->
		
		</BLOCKQUOTE>
	<H3>
	<A NAME="description"></A>
	DESCRIPTION
	</H3>
	<BLOCKQUOTE>
		<P>
		This section takes a task-oriented approach to describing the function
		of the proc, or built-in command. In general, the section describes
		the default behavior and then discusses notable options that modify
		the default behavior. These options often appear in a bulleted list of
		alternative or additional ways to use the command that allow you to
		customize its function to fit your needs.</P>

	</BLOCKQUOTE>
	<!-- no input sections for now
	<H3>
	<A NAME="input"></A>
	INPUT
	</H3>
	<BLOCKQUOTE>
		<P>
		Currently no e93 commands accept input from stdin.
		</P>
		
	</BLOCKQUOTE>
	-->
	<H3>
	<A NAME="output"></A>
	OUTPUT
	</H3>
	<BLOCKQUOTE>
		<P>
		This section describes the output of the command.
		Output can include none (no output), one or more files, or standard output.
		</P>

	</BLOCKQUOTE>
	<H3>
	<A NAME="status"></A>
	STATUS
	</H3>
	<BLOCKQUOTE>
		<P>
		This section lists the status codes that the command returns and their meanings.
		Note that these status codes are returned in the <VAR>errorInfo</VAR> variable
		and can be retrieved by using the command line</P>
		<P><CODE>
		puts $errorInfo
		</CODE></P>
		<P>
		A value of 0 indicates that no errors occurred; anything else indicates an error. </P>
		<P>
		Typical values are:<BR /><BR />
		</P>
		<P>
		<!-- Table Start -->
		<TABLE BORDER="0" CELLSPACING="0" CELLPADDING="0">
			<TR>
				<TD ROWSPAN="3" COLSPAN="1" WIDTH="51" ALIGN="left">
				</TD>
				<TD>
				<P>
				0</P>
				</TD>
				<TD>
				<P>
				no errors</P>
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
				<P>
				1 </P>
				</TD>
				<TD>
				<P>
				syntax error</P>
				</TD>
			</TR>
			<TR>
				<TD>
				<P>
				2</P>
				</TD>
				<TD>
				<P>
				execution error</P>
				</TD>
			</TR>
		</TABLE>
		<!-- Table End -->
		</P>
		<P>
		In general, .</P>
	</BLOCKQUOTE>

	<H3>
	<A NAME="parameters"></A>
	PARAMETERS
	</H3>
	<BLOCKQUOTE>
		<P>
		This section describes all the parameters that can be used with a particular proc, or built-in command.
		Parameters are position dependent, they appear in the order in which they must appear on the command line.
		</P>
		<P>
		Be careful not to confuse a parameter type with a specific instance of that parameter.
		A parameter such as <VAR>file1 ?file2?...</VAR>, which indicates that you can specify more than one file,
		is considered to be a single parameter type; <VAR>myFile</VAR> and <VAR>yourFile</VAR>
		are specific instances of that parameter.
		</P>
		
		<P>Some parameters may only have a one value from a mutualy exclusive list of values.
		Parameter values such as this are always shown in all capital letters.
		e.g. in the <VAR>relationship</VAR> parmeter to the
		<A HREF="commands/addmenu.html#relationship">addmenu</A> command.</P>
	</BLOCKQUOTE>
	<H3>
	<A NAME="options"></A>
	OPTIONS
	</H3>
	<BLOCKQUOTE>
		<P>
		This section describes all the command line options that can be used with a particular proc, or built-in command.
		You use them to tailor a command to your needs.
		</P>
		<P>
		You can distinguish options to the commands from parameters (which are most frequently buffer or window names) by the hyphen (<VAR>-</VAR>)
		that immediately precedes an option. This hyphen is part of the option and must always be included. </P>
		<P>
		Options can have their own parameters, which are also described in this section. In general, if you specify an option that has parameters,
		you must also specify at least one of its parameters.</P>
	</BLOCKQUOTE>
	<H3>
	<A NAME="examples"></A>
	EXAMPLES
	</H3>
	<BLOCKQUOTE>
		<P>
		Using one or more examples, this section illustrates the uses of a proc, or built-in command,
		either alone or within enclosing procs. Examples proceed from relatively easy tasks (often the default behavior)
		to more complicated ones (using multiple options) that are custom designed for a specific purpose.</P>
	</BLOCKQUOTE>
	<H3>
	<A NAME="limitations"></A>
	LIMITATIONS
	</H3>
	<BLOCKQUOTE>
		<P>
		This section is included for some commands to point out certain limitations,
		warnings, or special cases of which you should be aware. </P>
	</BLOCKQUOTE>
	<H3>
	<A NAME="seealso"></A>
	SEE ALSO
	</H3>
	<BLOCKQUOTE>
		<P>
		This section provides references to other relevant information.</P>
	</BLOCKQUOTE>
	<H3>
	<A NAME="location"></A>
	LOCATION
	</H3>
	<BLOCKQUOTE>
		<P>
		This section, in the case of Tcl procedures (procs), list the name of the .tcl file that contains the proc.</P>
	</BLOCKQUOTE>
</BODY>
</CHAPTER>
