<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="chapters.css"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="chapters.xsl"?>

<CHAPTER>

<TITLE>
Copyright Information
</TITLE>

<SUMMARY>
Copyright information about e93 and its components
</SUMMARY>

<BODY>

<H2>
e93 Copyrights
</H2>


<P>e93 is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the e93 LICENSE AGREEMENT.</P>

<P>e93 is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY
WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. e93 is a copyrighted program
authored by Todd Squires and owned by Core Technologies. By continuing
the installation of this program, by loading or running the program,
or by placing or copying the program onto your computer hard drive,
you are agreeing to be bound by the terms of this License Agreement.
e93 is not being sold or offered for sale by Core Technologies. You
may, however, without charge, use, modify and distribute exact or
modified copies of e93 and its documentation subject to the following
limitations:

<UL>
<LI>
You may make and keep as many copies of
the e93 files as you wish.</LI>

<LI>
You may distribute copies of the e93 files
to others provided you distribute ALL the files included in e93 provided
that you (1) appropriately publish on each copy an appropriate copyright
notice and disclaimer of warranty, (2) keep all notices with respect to
this License Agreement intact and (3) give any other recipients of e93
a copy of this License Agreement.</LI>

<LI>
You may charge for such distribution,
provided that you inform your prospective customers that the payment is
only for the distribution and not for e93.</LI>

<LI>
You may provide e93 along with another
product or service, even if you charge for that product or service, provided
that your prospective customers or clients are aware that they are NOT
paying for e93 and that any modified files carry a prominent notice stating
that you changed the file and the date of such changes.</LI>

<LI>
You agree that e93 will not be shipped,
transferred or exported into any country in violation of the U.S. Export
Administration Act and that you will not utilize, in any other manner,
e93 in violation of any applicable law.</LI>

<LI>
e93 and the accompanying documentation
is owned by Core Technologies and is protected by United States copyright
laws and international treaty provisions. You must treat e93 like any other
copyrighted material, except that you may make copies of the exact or modified
e93 files to give to other persons provided that you (1) appropriately
publish on each copy an appropriate copyright notice and disclaimer of
warranty, (2) keep all notices with respect to this License Agreement intact
and (3) give any other recipients of e93 a copy of this License Agreement.</LI>

<LI>
You agree to use your best efforts to
see that any user of e93 licensed hereunder complies with this License
Agreement.</LI>

<LI>
Since e93 has been made available free
of charge, you must agree not to hold or assert that Core Technologies
is liable for any damages resulting from the use of or inability to use
this software. CORE TECHNOLOGIES SPECIFICALLY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES,
EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO IMPLIED WARRANTIES OR
MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NON-INFRINGEMENT
OF THIRD PARTY RIGHTS. CORE TECHNOLOGIES does not warrant that the operation
of e93 will be uninterrupted, error free or meet licensee's specific requirements.
The agents, employees, and distributors of e93 are not authorized to make
any warranties on behalf of CORE TECHNOLOGIES. In no event shall CORE TECHNOLOGIES
be liable for any loss of profit or any other commercial damage, including
but not limited to special, incidental, consequential or other damages,
arising out of the use or inability to use e93, including but not limited
to loss of data or data being rendered inaccurate or losses sustained by
third parties. e93 IS NOT LICENSED TO BE USED AT ALL IN PLACES WHERE THIS
EXCLUSION IS NOT LEGAL.</LI>

<LI>
Neither this License Agreement nor any
part or portion hereof shall be assigned or sublicensed, except as described
herein. Should any provision of this License Agreement be held to be void,
invalid, unenforceable or illegal by a court, the validity and enforceability
of the other provisions shall not be affected thereby. If any provision
is determined to be unenforceable, you agree to a modification of such
provision to provide for enforcement of the provision's intent, to the
extent permitted by applicable law. Failure of a party to enforce any provision
of this License Agreement shall not constitute or be construed as a waiver
of such provision or of the right to enforce such provision. If you fail
to comply with any terms of the License Agreement, YOUR LICENSE IS AUTOMATICALLY
TERMINATED.</LI>
</UL>
</P>

<P>
<BR />YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU HAVE READ
THIS AGREEMENT, YOU UNDERSTAND THIS AGREEMENT, AND UNDERSTAND THAT BY CONTINUING
THE INSTALLATION OF THE SOFTWARE, BY LOADING OR RUNNING THE SOFTWARE, OR
BY PLACING OR COPYING THE SOFTWARE ONTO YOUR COMPUTER HARD DRIVE, YOU AGREE
TO BE BOUND BY THIS AGREEMENT'S TERMS AND CONDITIONS. YOU FURTHER AGREE
THAT, EXCEPT FOR WRITTEN SEPARATE AGREEMENTS BETWEEN CORE TECHNOLOGIES
AND YOU, THIS AGREEMENT IS A COMPLETE AND EXCLUSIVE STATEMENT OF THE RIGHTS
AND LIABILITIES OF THE PARTIES. THIS AGREEMENT SUPERSEDES ALL PRIOR ORAL
AGREEMENTS, PROPOSALS OR UNDERSTANDINGS, AND ANY OTHER COMMUNICATIONS BETWEEN
CORE TECHNOLOGIES AND YOU RELATING TO THE SUBJECT MATTER OF THIS AGREEMENT.
</P>

<H2>
Regular Expression Copyrights
</H2>

<P>
Regular expression material is derived
from The GNU Emacs Manual, 9th edition. Copyright 1985, 1986, 1987, 1993
Free Software Foundation, Inc. and from the GNU regex library version 0.11.
Copyright 1992 Free Software Foundation, Inc.
The Free Software Foundation gives
permission for the use of this material in e93, with different distribution
terms from those stated in the Emacs manual, because e93 is free software,
and thus worthy of cooperation.
</P>

<H2>
Tcl Copyrights
</H2>

<P>
Tcl software is copyrighted by the
Regents of the University of California, Sun Microsystems, Inc., and other
parties. The following terms apply to all files associated with the software
unless explicitly disclaimed in individual files.
The authors hereby grant permission
to use, copy, modify, distribute, and license this software and its documentation
for any purpose, provided that existing copyright notices are retained
in all copies and that this notice is included verbatim in any distributions.
No written agreement, license, or royalty fee is required for any of the
authorized uses. Modifications to this software may be copyrighted by their
authors and need not follow the licensing terms described here, provided
that the new terms are clearly indicated on the first page of each file
where they apply.<BR />
IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR DISTRIBUTORS
BE LIABLE TO ANY PARTY FOR DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL
DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, ITS DOCUMENTATION, OR
ANY DERIVATIVES THEREOF, EVEN IF THE AUTHORS HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY
OF SUCH DAMAGE.
THE AUTHORS AND DISTRIBUTORS SPECIFICALLY
DISCLAIM ANY WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES
OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, AND NON-INFRINGEMENT.
THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS, AND THE AUTHORS AND DISTRIBUTORS
HAVE NO OBLIGATION TO PROVIDE MAINTENANCE, SUPPORT, UPDATES, ENHANCEMENTS,
OR MODIFICATIONS.<BR />
GOVERNMENT USE: If you are acquiring
this software on behalf of the U.S. government, the Government shall have
only "Restricted Rights" in the software and related documentation as defined
in the Federal Acquisition Regulations (FARs) in Clause 52.227.19 (c) (2).
If you are acquiring the software on behalf of the Department of Defense,
the software shall be classified as "Commercial Computer Software" and
the Government shall have only "Restricted Rights" as defined in Clause
252.227-7013 (c) (1) of DFARs. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the authors
grant the U.S. Government and others acting in its behalf permission to
use and distribute the software in accordance with the terms specified
in this license.
</P>
</BODY>
</CHAPTER>
