<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="chapters.css"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="chapters.xsl"?>

<CHAPTER>
<TITLE>Keyboard Input</TITLE>

<SUMMARY>
Key types
</SUMMARY>

<BODY>
<P>e93 separates the keyboard into three types of keys: modifiers, characters, and functions.</P>
<BLOCKQUOTE>
	<H3>Modifiers</H3>
	<BLOCKQUOTE>
		<P>There are 11 modifier keys defined by e93:</P>
		<BLOCKQUOTE>
			<P>caps-lock<BR />
			shift<BR />
			control<BR />
			modifier 0 (<A HREF="standardkeyboardlayout.html#CommandKey">Command Key</A>)<BR />
			modifier 1 - modifier 7(implementation specific)</P>
		</BLOCKQUOTE>
	</BLOCKQUOTE>

	<H3>Characters</H3>
	<BLOCKQUOTE>
		<P>The character keys are a-z, numbers, tab, escape, return, etc...<BR />
		These are the keys that would be expected to insert a character when typed.<BR />
		On MSWindows this includes characters that require multiple keystrokes to produce on some keyboards.
		e.g. "Alt+ 0 2 5 2" on the numeric keypad, which produces '&#252;'.</P>
		<!--
			I messed around for a while before I found out that umlaut u was &#252 in SGML,
			the Windows escape sequence might have been a clue, duh.
		-->
	</BLOCKQUOTE>

	<H3>Function keys</H3>
	<BLOCKQUOTE>
		<P>The function keys are:<BR />
		Arrows, Backspace, F1, F2, Undo, Help, Break, etc... These are keys that do not insert characters, but instead, perform actions.</P>
	</BLOCKQUOTE>
</BLOCKQUOTE>


<P>When no keys are bound (See the section on Key binding below), e93 relies on a default set of bindings that are "hardwired" into the code.</P>
<P><B>NOTE:</B> Key bindings can be used to override this default behavior.</P>

<P>Here is a list of keys, and default actions:</P>

<P>All unmodified, or shift modified characters are inserted into the active window.</P>

<P>Unmodified Arrows move the cursor up/down by line, left/right by character.<BR />
Control Left/Right Arrow moves cursor by word left/right.<BR />
Control Up/Down Arrow scrolls the document down/up without moving the cursor.<BR />
<!--
Control is Alt (for some things) on Windows if Control is mapped to command
-->
<A HREF="standardkeyboardlayout.html#CommandKey">Command</A> Left/Right moves to start or end of line.<BR />
<A HREF="standardkeyboardlayout.html#CommandKey">Command</A> Up/Down moves up or down by page.<BR />
Shift can be used with the above combinations to expand the selection.</P>

<P>Page up, Page down move the cursor up or down by a page.<BR />
Shift can be used with the page up/down to expand the selection.</P>

<P>Home, and End move the cursor to the start or end of a line.<BR />
<A HREF="standardkeyboardlayout.html#CommandKey">Command</A> Home/End moves to start/end of the document.<BR />
Shift can be used with the home/end to expand the selection.</P>

<P>Unmodified Backspace deletes the character to the left of the cursor.</P>
<!--
Backspace is not working on Windows. Windows has no "option" key. WinKey isn't working as option yet (perhaps never).

Command Backspace deletes to end of line.
Command Shift Backspace deletes to beginning of line.
Command Option Backspace deletes to end of buffer.
Command Shift Option Backspace deletes to beginning of buffer.
Control Backspace deletes word left.
Control Shift Backspace deletes word right.
-->

<P>Unmodified Delete deletes the character to the right of the cursor.<BR />
<A HREF="standardkeyboardlayout.html#CommandKey">Command</A> Delete deletes to beginning of line.<BR />
<!--
Command Option Delete deletes to beginning of buffer.
Command Shift Option Delete deletes to end of buffer.
-->
<A HREF="standardkeyboardlayout.html#CommandKey">Command</A> Shift Delete deletes to end of line.</P>
<!--
Escape inserts an escape (except in some dialogs windows where it
selects the "Cancel" option). NOTE: if you wish to insert an escape
character into the text of a dialog window, type Control [.
-->

<P>Return does an autoindent (except in some dialog windows where it selects the "Ok" option.)</P>

<BLOCKQUOTE>
	<P><B>NOTE:</B> If you wish to place a new-line character into the text of a dialog window, type Control J.</P>
</BLOCKQUOTE>

<P>Tab inserts a tab (except in some dialog windows where it may move between fields.)</P>

<BLOCKQUOTE>
	<P><B>NOTE:</B> If you wish to insert a tab character into the text of a dialog window, type Control I.</P>
</BLOCKQUOTE>

<P>Escape inserts an escape (except in some dialog windows where it selects the "Cancel" option.)</P>

<BLOCKQUOTE>
	<P><B>NOTE:</B> If you wish to insert an escape character into the text of a dialog window, type Control [.</P>
</BLOCKQUOTE>

<P>Cut, Copy, Paste, Undo, and Redo (if you have these keys) perform their respective actions.</P>

</BODY>
</CHAPTER>
