<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="chapters.css"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="chapters.xsl"?>

<CHAPTER>
<TITLE>Selections</TITLE>

<SUMMARY>
Special text selection features
</SUMMARY>

<BODY>
<P>e93's selection mechanism is on of its more distinguishing
features. At first glance, e93 selects text in the same way as many
other modern editors, namely:</P>

<P>To select text for cut, copy, paste, or other operations, first
move the mouse pointer to the position where the selection should
begin, click the left button, and while holding it down, drag the
mouse pointer to the end of the desired selection. The process
"highlights" the selected text (by drawing it in inverse colors.) The
highlighted selection can then be operated on by a number of editor
functions. e93 also supports word, line, and document selection by
double, triple, and quadruple clicking respectively. (Double clicking
is clicking the mouse button twice in rapid succession.) If you double
click, holding the left button down after the second click, e93 will
the select words as you drag the mouse along. This also works for
lines when triple clicking.</P>

<P>To adjust a selection, hold down the shift key on the keyboard, and
click the left mouse button in the document. This will either enlarge,
or reduce the current selection, depending on where you click.
Clicking outside the current selection will enlarge it so that it
extends to the point where you clicked. Clicking inside the selection
will reduce it by pulling the nearest edge in to the point where you
clicked. You can also shift-double, shift-triple or shift-quadruple
click, and get the expected results.</P>

<A NAME="Segmented"></A>
<H3>Segmented Selection</H3>
<BLOCKQUOTE>
<P>A powerful feature of e93 not found in most other modern editors is
known as "Segmented Selection." This means is that e93 is capable of
creating a discontiguous selection (one which has "holes" in it.) This
feature is used by e93 to implement a more familiar form of
selection:</P>
</BLOCKQUOTE>

<H3>Columnar Selection</H3>
<BLOCKQUOTE>
	<P>To create a columnar selection, click the right mouse button (if
	your mouse has more than one button) and drag the mouse over the
	document. This will create a selection that is rectangular.</P>

	<P><B>NOTE:</B> If your mouse only has one button, you can create a
	columnar selection by holding the "Command" key on the keyboard down,
	while clicking and dragging. You would typically use columnar
	selection to manipulate data that appears in columns of text. As
	above, double clicking will force the selection to begin and end at
	word boundaries. Triple and quadruple clicking will also work as
	expected. You can also use the shift key as described above to expand
	or reduce the columnar selection.</P>

	<P><B>NOTE:</B> Although a columnar selection looks rectangular to
	you, it is important to understand that e93 does not really think of
	it that way. As far as e93 is concerned, a columnar selection is
	nothing more than a discontinuous selection that spans pieces of the
	text. (In this case, a small portion of one line, followed by portion
	of the line below it, and so on...) This distinction will become
	important as operations that work on selections are discussed.</P>

</BLOCKQUOTE>
</BODY>
</CHAPTER>
