<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="chapters.css"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="chapters.xsl"?>

<CHAPTER>
<TITLE>
Syntax Maps
</TITLE>

<SUMMARY>
Information about syntax maps
</SUMMARY>

<BODY>
<P><B>VERY PRELIMINARY DOCUMENTATION ON SYNTAX MAPS</B></P>

<P><B>NOTE:</B> while reading this, it will be very helpful to be looking
at an <A HREF="commands/addsyntaxmap.html"><CODE>addsyntaxmap</CODE></A> command from the e93rc.tcl file....</P>

<P>The <A HREF="commands/addsyntaxmap.html"><CODE>addsyntaxmap</CODE></A> command in Tcl creates a new syntax map.</P>

<P>A syntax map is the data structure which gives e93 all the information
it needs to search through a document, and apply styles to the text
which the map specifies.</P>

<P>The first argument of the addsyntaxmap command is the name of the map,
and the second argument is the mapping data itself.</P>

<P>Syntax maps are assigned to e93 windows with the command:
<CODE><A HREF="commands/setsyntaxmap.html">setsyntaxmap</A> <VAR>bufferName</VAR> <VAR>syntaxMapName</VAR></CODE></P>

<P>The mapping data is composed of keyword, parameter pairs. The only
valid keywords are:</P>

<UL>
<LI>exp</LI>
<LI>map</LI>
<LI>at</LI>
<LI>root</LI>
</UL>

<P>"exp" defines a regular expression in the map. You can define as many
as you want but the more you have, the slower the highlighting. The 2
parameters to exp are simply its name, and the expression being
defined. The expressions are matched using e93's regular expression
matching routines (The same ones which are used when you specify a
regular expression in the "Find" dialog.)</P>

<P>"map" describes how expressions are mapped to styles. There are 6
parameters to the map command.</P>

<P>The first is the name of the map. This will be important later. The
second parameter is the name of the expression which introduces a
given mapping -- it is called the start expression.</P>

<P>The third parameter is a (potentially empty) list of names of ending
expressions.
</P>

<P>The remaining 3 parameters are the start-style, the between-style, and
the end-style. Styles are nothing more than integers which index
styles assigned to text. You can assign styles to the text by using
e93's commands:</P>

<P><CODE><A HREF="commands/setcolors.html">setcolors</A> <VAR>windowName foregroundColor backgroundColor ?styleNum?</VAR></CODE></P>
<P><CODE><A HREF="commands/setfont.html">setfont</A> <VAR>windowName fontName ?styleNum?</VAR></CODE></P>

<P>maps work like this:</P>
<P>If e93 encounters text which matches the starting expression, it is
colored in start-style. If the list of ending expressions is
non-empty, then e93 searches for text which matches any of the ending
expressions. The text between the start and ending expression is
colored in the between-style. Finally, the text of the matching ending
expression is colored in the end-style. If the ending expression list
is empty, then e93 ends the mapping immediately after the text which
matches the start expression.</P>

<P>The "at" keyword is used to tell e93 which mappings to search for, and
when. "at" works like this: The first parameter is the name of the
mapping during which this "at" takes place -- the "parent map". The
next parameter is a list of mappings which are allowed to start within
the "parent map".</P>

<P>During the text between the starting and ending expressions of a given
mapping, e93 will search for the starting expressions of any mapping
which is specified by an "at" command for the given mapping.</P>

<P>The "root" keyword is just a special case of "at". It tells which
mappings are in effect when no other mapping is in effect.</P>

<P>As an example, consider rules to color 'C' strings. To color them, you
need to locate the start quote, and the end quote. But, while looking
at the string, you may encounter a '&#092;' character which tells 'C' to
treat the next character specially. So.... The mapping would look like
this:
</P>
<PRE>
<CODE>addsyntaxmap "C Strings" &#092;
{
  exp {e_string_delimiter  "&#092;""} &lt;&lt;&lt; expression which matches a double quote character
  exp {e_quoted_char       "&#092;&#092;&#092;&#092;&#092;[-&#092;]"} &lt;&lt;&lt; expression which matches a &#092; followed by ANYTHING

  map {m_string             e_string_delimiter {e_string_delimiter} $style_delimiter $style_string $style_delimiter}
  map {m_string_quoted_char e_quoted_char      {}                   $style_char      0             0}

  at {m_string             {m_string_quoted_char}} &lt;&lt;&lt; within strings, look for &#092;'s

  root {m_string}          &lt;&lt;&lt; look for strings at the root level
}
</CODE></PRE>

<P><B>NOTE:</B> in the above example, &#092;'s need to be quoted multiple times to
hide them from Tcl.</P>

<P>So, if you are not thoroughly confused, you are ready to write
syntax highlighting rules. :-)</P>

<P>There is one more tiny little detail that is very useful, but
was difficult to explain in the midst of the discussion above.</P>

<P>When specifying a "map", the start and end expressions are allowed to
take the form:</P>

<P><CODE>e_expressionName:#</CODE></P>

<P>where # is a number from 0-9. This number corresponds to the tagged part
of the regular expression given by e_expressionName.
For instance, if I had an expression, say...</P>
        <P><CODE>exp {e_sample_expression    "([a-z]+)([0-9]+)"}</CODE></P>

<P>I could have a mapping:</P>

<BLOCKQUOTE>
	<P><CODE>map {m_sample_mapping    e_sample_expression:0    {}    $style_blah  0   0}</CODE></P>
</BLOCKQUOTE>

<P>This means that the entire expression e_sample_expression needs to be
matched to start the mapping, but that the part which is used as the
start-expression is simply the [a-z]+ (tag 0)</P>
</BODY>
</CHAPTER>
