<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="chapters.css"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="chapters.xsl"?>

<CHAPTER>
<TITLE>Windows and Buffers</TITLE>

<SUMMARY>
What a buffer is and how it relates to a window
</SUMMARY>

<BODY>

<P>When e93 opens a file for editing, it reads the contents of the
file into a "buffer", and then closes the file. All editing takes
place within the buffer, and changes are not written back to the file
until the buffer is "Saved".</P>

<P>A buffer is an area of memory where text is stored while it is
being edited. Buffers can contain arbitrary amounts of text, and do not
place any limits on the characters they contain ('ASCII 0' is allowed
in a buffer). Although buffers are usually used to hold the contents
of files, they are also used to hold other things, like new documents,
clipboards, and the text that is used by the Find and Replace
functions.</P>

<P>All buffers have names. These names are needed so that buffers can
be referred to from Tcl scripts. The name of each buffer must be
unique. Buffer names can be of arbitrary length, and can contain any
character except 'ASCII 0'. A buffer opened to a file is typically named
with the full path name of that file. Buffer names are case
sensitive.</P>

<P>Buffers can have "windows" associated with them. A window can be
thought of as a view onto the contents of a buffer. Windows are where
most editing commands are carried out. It is important to understand
that buffers do not NEED to have windows associated with them. In
fact, certain buffers (like clipboards) typically are not associated
with windows.</P>

<P>Each window on the other hand, is always associated with a buffer.
Windows also have names, and each takes the name of the buffer that it
is associated with.</P>

<P>Many of the features of a window can be changed from Tcl scripts.</P>
<BLOCKQUOTE>
	<P>
	Some of these are:<BR />
	<A HREF="commands/setcolors.html">Foreground Color</A><BR />
	<A HREF="commands/setcolors.html">Background Color</A><BR />
	<A HREF="commands/setfont.html">Font</A><BR />
	<A HREF="commands/settabsize.html">Tab Size</A><BR />
	<A HREF="commands/settopleft.html">Location</A><BR />
    <A HREF="commands/setrect.html">Width/Height</A><BR />
	</P>
</BLOCKQUOTE>

<P>See <a href="commands.html">Command Reference</a> for detailed
information on commands that modify windows.</P>

<P>e93 maintains the concept of an "active window". This is the window
that is top-most. Most menu commands operate on the active window.</P>

<P>Each window has a "Status bar" which gives useful information about
the buffer being edited. The status bar indicates if a buffer has been
modified, how many lines of text it contains, how many characters of
text it contains, and gives information about the current
cursor/selection position. Also, if there is a task running in the
window, the status bar will let you know.</P>

<h3>
SEE ALSO
</h3>
<blockquote>
<p><code>
    <A HREF="colors.html">Color Names</A>
    <A HREF="syntaxmaps.html">Syntax Maps</A>
    <A HREF="commands/openwindow.html">openwindow</A>
    <A HREF="commands/setcolors.html">setcolors</A>
    <A HREF="commands/setfont.html">setfont</A>
    <A HREF="commands/settabsize.html">settabsize</A>
    <A HREF="commands/settopleft.html">settopleft</A>
    <A HREF="commands/setrect.html">setrect</A>
</code></p> 
</blockquote>

</BODY>
</CHAPTER>
